## **MIRAJ ARYAL**

#### 0411381165 | mirajaryal@gmail.com

## **Professional Summary**

A Full Stack Developer with knowledge in different frontend and backend languages, responsive frameworks, databases, and best code practices. My objective is simply to be the best developer that I can be and to contribute to the technology industry. I am dedicated to perfecting my craft by self-learning and from experienced developers, remaining humble, and continuously making strides to learn all that I can about standard web development. I have over 2 years of experience in developing premium websites. I have mostly worked as a sole developer in my previous role but would prefer working in a team where sharing and growth is greater comparatively to working solo.

#### **Technical Skills**

**Web Technologies:** React, Next.js, GraphQL, REST API, Vanilla JS, jQuery, PHP/MySQL, Advanced WordPress, Contentful, Strapi.js, Firebase, HTML/CSS, Styled Components, Material UI, TailwindCSS, Chakra UI, Bootstrap, Google Analytics, EDM (Mailchimp), WebFlow.

Familiar with: Angular JS 1.x, Node.js, Python

**Frameworks:** Codelgniter, Laravel, Yii2 **Database:** MySQL, MongoDB (Basics)

Tools: VSCode, Bracket, Atlassian Tools Suite (Jira, Confluence), Virtual Box, Asana, Slack, MAMP, WAMP

Platforms: Windows, Mac

Version Control: GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket

## **Professional Experience**

#### **Full-Stack Developer**

Mar 2021 - Present

**RAW STUDIO, Town Hall, NSW** 

- Take ownership and be responsible for the development of project from start to finish.
- Meeting with clients to understand and document project requirements and work closely with them to ensure the requirement is met.
- Developed Homepage for a SPA of our recent client Zip Co which utilized recent technology like
   Next.js with Typescript for Frontend, Material UI and Styled Components for styling and
   Headless CMS Contentful for Backend using GraphQL to inject data through API to frontend.
- Developed quick and small-scale projects using Webflow.

#### Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

#### **Full-Stack Developer**

Sept 2020 - Feb 2021

#### **PICTURA CREATIVE, North Sydney, NSW**

- Solely responsible for development of project throughout till it is live and hand-overed to client.
- Develop the websites using **Advanced WordPress** for different service-based clients like Home Builders, Hotel, Online Shopping, Trade Services, etc.
- Write effective codes to match as close as possible to the design.
- Write **reusable code components** using Advanced Custom Field to build custom CMS in order to increase flexibility and avoid use of page builders.
- Test websites to ensure responsiveness and efficiency, implement latest CSS techniques like flexbox and grid to achieve complex responsive layouts.
- Integrate **payment gateways** like Stripe, PayPal, AfterPay to ecommerce websites.
- Developed the website that is **SEO ready**, has full control over H tags without affecting the design.
- Implement Avanser, Google Analytics, Google Search Console and Google Tag Manager.
- Achieved a Lighthouse score of 70+ on frontend.
- **Cross Browser testing** using VM Virtual Box to ensure the website functions correctly over all or most of the browsers.
- Deliver clean and functional code within a timely manner.
- Perform **domain registration**, **cPanel** configuration, SSL certification, etc to ensure website registration and **hosting** task is completed and recorded in WHMCS.

## **Web Developer (Contract Job)**

Jan 2020 – Mar 2020

#### SPARK INTERACT, Marrickville, NSW

- Joined to support the overseas dev team working on a PHP application for a hospital in Vietnam.
- Served as a bridge between the overseas dev team and the Production Manager, cross-check the
  codes implemented by the developers; address and fix the issues if any, implement any changes or
  ideas as required.
- Troubleshoot any errors in the websites of existing client.
- Write a report on functionality, interactivity and responsiveness of websites and report it to the Production Manager.

### Web Developer (Part-time)

Jun 2017 - Nov 2019

#### **EVEREST VIEW TRAVEL & TOURS, Rockdale, NSW**

- Developed websites and web apps for ticket management system, special request page, travel forum, etc. using PHP/MySQL.
- Use of mailer libraries like **PHPMailer**, Swiftmailer for powerful component-based mailing for PHP based websites.
- Implemented business ideas from owner into web application, creating an effective bridge between customer and the business.
  - For example: Created manage booking website where customers can request for flight change, seat allocation, flight cancellation, special meal request or special need request to the travel agency online through the <u>manage booking website</u>.

#### Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

#### PHP Developer Feb 2014 - Mar 2015

#### **IMAGINE WEB SOLUTION, Kathmandu, Nepal**

- Wrote Procedural and OOP PHP codes to develop a website.
- Developed different websites using **MVC** framework, **CodeIgniter** mostly.
- Experience integrating with backend RESTFUL APIs.
- SVN for project version control.
- Developed several websites for Education, Medical, E-commerce sector.
- Onsite Communication with clients and handle modification quickly.

#### **Education**

# Master of Technology (Software Engineering) Federation University, Australia Bachelor of Computer Science & Engineering ANNA University, India

#### **Personal Skills**

- **Fast Learner**: Ability to grasp new technology in short time and implement it. Recently started working on Advanced WordPress and solely completed development of 3 major projects.
- **Knowledge, Creativity and Problem Solving**: Good understanding of programming concept which helps in problem-solving and be creative with logics to achieve expected output.
- **Dedication**: I tend to give my all when I'm doing a project. I enjoy my work and take pride in it. I work off hours to learn and experiment new things that would help me achieve better output.
- **Passion for Knowledge**: I'm very excited to learn and grasp new technologies and update my skills.
- **Punctual**: I'm always on time unless affected by any external factor.

## **Achievements/Awards**

- Invited to the exclusive Golden Key International Honour Society for outstanding academic achievement.
- Commendation letter from university for outstanding academic performance in Semester 2

#### **Hobbies**

- Art & Photography: Facebook Page
- Music: YouTube Channel
- Cooking: Chef @Bondi Icebergs Group, La Rosa The Strand, Keg & Brew Hotel

#### References

Available upon request.